eurobrussels.com 2019-04-26

# Privacy Policy | EuroBrussels

EuroJobsites and its affiliates (collectively "EuroJobsites") respect individuals' concerns about privacy. Your visit to this website (the "Site") is subject to the terms set out in this Privacy Policy and to our Terms of Use.

This Privacy Policy describes the types of personal data we collect, how we use that data, who it is shared with, how we look after it, and how you can access and control it.

The entity responsible for the collection and processing of data under this policy is EuroJobsites Ltd. EuroJobsites Ltd is a UK company registered number 4694396, and registered address is EuroJobsites Ltd, Unit 8, Kingsmill Business Park, Kingston Upon Thames, London, KT1 3GZ, United Kingdom.

## 1.1 Website usage

EuroJobsites collect information on web site usage to enable us to monitor usage of the web sites. This information includes the number of visitors, the pages they visit, and the length of each visit. This information is only published in aggregate statistics.

## 1.2 Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies

EuroJobsites and our third-party partners, such as our advertising and analytics partners, use cookies and other tracking technologies to provide functionality and to recognize you across different Services and devices.

## 2.1 Newsletter and Job Alerts

We store your email address if you subscribe to one of our newsletters. If you subscribe to Job Alerts, we store your email address and the selection of categories and countries you have selected to receive Job Alerts for. Your email address and other information will only be used for sending you our newsletter and/or Job Alerts and will not be passed to any other company.

## 2.2 Job Applications through EuroJobsites website forms

For some jobs you may be applying by entering information into a website form on a EuroJobsites job-board. In these cases the recruiting organisation (the Recruiter) has requested that EuroJobsites collects your application data in EuroJobsites’ Applicant Tracker System.

EuroJobsites holds all answers and documents from a Job Application for the sole use of the Recruiter. Once the Recruiter informs EuroJobsites the recruitment has been completed, EuroJobsites will remove or anonymise all personal data from the job application from EuroJobsites systems.

EuroJobsites will not use your personal data supplied in the job application for any purpose except to enable the Recruiter to receive it or manage it for their recruitment.

## 2.3 CV database

As a job seeker, you can submit your CV and other personal data to EuroJobsites for posting on our Site and storage in our CV database. The personal data that you submit will only be used for recruitment purposes, which include EuroJobsites and recruiters evaluating and contacting you regarding your interest in employment, and forwarding your candidature to potential recruiters.

## 2.4 Social Media

If you interact with EuroJobsites on social media platforms such as Facebook and Twitter EuroJobsites may obtain information about you. The information we receive will depend on the privacy preferences you have set on those types of platforms.

## 2.5 Login

If you create a Job Alert you may use a password to login, which we store securely in encrypted form. If you login using Google or Facebook we simply confirm with them that you are also currently also logged in with them using the email address you provided and this then proves your identity.

## 2.6 Your emails to us

Emails to us from jobseekers, candidates or clients are held in a cloud based email management system. Emails from candidates or jobseekers to us and replies are retained until we have concluded the conversation, then the email is removed within 1 month. Emails to or from clients (usually regarding sales or job postings) are retained for a maximum of 10 years from the last contact.

## 3.1 General information

EuroJobsites do not sell, rent, trade or otherwise disclose personal data about our Site visitors, except as described here.   
When you provide EuroJobsites with personal data through this Site, you authorise EuroJobsites to use that personal data for the indicated purposes.

## 3.2 CV database profile

When you upload your personal data to the CV Database you authorise us to use that personal data for the purposes described in our CV Terms Of Use.

EuroJobsites operatives, agents or subcontractors, will use this for recruitment purposes, which include evaluating and contacting you regarding your interest in employment, and forwarding your candidature to potential recruiters.

We may share your personal data with potential recruiters. Recruiters will have access to our candidates database remotely. We contractually require the potential recruiters to keep the data secure and not to use them for other purposes than recruitment purposes. Once contacted by a potential recruiter, please see their privacy policy for more information about their privacy practices.

Additionally, we may provide these potential recruiters with aggregated information (generic information on users of our services) about the performance of the Site such as the number of visitors, their country of residence, age, gender and language preferences.

## 3.3 EuroJobsites aim to store candidate personal data in the EU/EEA/UK

Personal candidate information held by EuroJobsites is generally stored within the EU/EEA/UK. Therefore EuroJobsites websites, servers running websites and databases are located within the EU/EEA/UK. EuroJobsites Newsletter, Job Alerts, Job Application and CV database systems hold your personal data on databases and servers within the EU/EEA/UK.

## 3.4 Service providers not located in the EU/EEA/UK

For a few services, mainly for handling client, sales and analytics information, EuroJobsites use US companies which may process your information outside the EU/EEA/UK.   
If you send emails to EuroJobsites this is read and managed using a system provided by a US based supplier. EuroJobsites may also store some personal data in Google Analytics, Google Docs, Google Drive or Dropbox, which are US based suppliers.  
These service providers all participate in and certify their compliance with the EU-US Privacy Shield Framework, which means these Suppliers undertake to make sure that the privacy rights of EU/EEA/UK individuals can be exercised when their data are being processed in the United States including safeguards on US government access to data.

## 3.5 Recruiters from outside the EU/EEA/UK may advertise jobs

Some recruiters advertising jobs on our websites or emails may have some operations outside of the EU/EEA/UK. Therefore if you apply for a job some of your personal data may leave the EU/EEA/UK, even if the job is located inside the EU/EEA/UK. Please consult the recruiter’s privacy policy for more details before applying.

## 3.6 Recruiters from outside the EU/EEA/UK may use the CV database

If you upload your personal details to the CV database your data may be viewed and your CV downloaded by a recruiter outside the EU/EEA/UK.

## 3.7 Third parties suppliers and subcontractors

EuroJobsites uses third parties and subcontractors to perform services such as email services, analytics, server hosting, and data processing. These third parties and subcontractors are subject to strict data processing terms and conditions and are contractually prohibited from utilising, sharing or retaining your personal data for any purpose other than as they have been specifically contracted for (or without your consent).

## 4.1 Amending or unsubscribing from Job Alerts or Newsletter

You can update your Job Alert subscription by clicking the preferences link at the bottom of the Job Alert. You can remove your subscription to a Newsletter or Job Alert at any time by clicking on the unsubscribe link at the bottom of the Newsletter or Job Alert.

## 4.2 Amending job applications

If you apply for a job, your application including a CV or other personal information is passed to the Recruiter or held temporarily by EuroJobsites for the Recruiter’s sole use. EuroJobsites are not able to amend this information as it is controlled by the Recruiter. You must contact the recruiter to update your application information.

## 4.3 Updating or removing your CV database information

You can login and update or remove your CV and details at any time. [Click here to login to the CV database](https://eurobrussels.com/cv). If you do not login or indicate you wish to continue within 27 months we automatically delete your CV from our system and remove your candidate profile from our database. If you have forgotten your password you can request a new one from the above link.

## 4.4 Your rights as a data subject

Under EU and UK data protection law, you have certain rights over the personal information that we hold about you. Here is a summary of the rights that usually apply:  
You have the right to request access to the personal data that we hold about you.  
You have the right to have inaccurate or incomplete information we hold about you corrected.  
You have the right to ask us to delete some or all of your personal information.  
You have the right to move, copy or transfer your personal information (“data portability”).  
You have the right to restrict processing of your personal information.  
You have the right to complain to the Information Commissioner’s Office in the UK with whom EuroJobsites Limited is registered (number ZA385671) and which enforces data protection laws. More information at https://ico.org.uk/.

In most cases you can access, correct, erase or download your information yourself by logging in to our systems (see ”How to access and control your information” above).

If you want to access, remove or correct information that you can’t do from a login to our systems, please send us a description of the information and what you wish us to do with it to dataprotection@eurojobsites.com. 

Please note that exceptions apply to a number of these rights, and not all rights will be applicable in all circumstances. For more details you should consult the guidance published by the Information Commissioner’s Office.

## 5.1 Data Retention

EuroJobsites only retains personal data for as long as needed to fulfill the purposes for which they were collected, unless otherwise provided by law. When the data is no longer necessary to meet the purposes for which it was collected, it is deleted or anonymised. We review our retention periods on a regular basis.

We automatically remove personal information from our CV database if you have not logged in or updated the data for 27 months.

Job applications made through EuroJobsites' systems are held on behalf of the recruiter. 6 months after the relevant job has expired all personal application details are automatically anonymised and the CVs deleted. 

Emails from candidates or jobseekers to us and replies are retained until we have concluded the conversation, then the email is removed within 1 month. Emails to or from clients (usually regarding sales or job postings) are retained for 10 years from the last contact.

## 5.2 Keeping your information safe

When you give us personal information, we take steps to ensure that appropriate technical and organisational controls are in place to protect it.

When you provide data via EuroJobsites websites or the CV database the connection uses SSL which encrypts and protects the data in transit so it reaches us securely. Passwords are held in encrypted form.

The database, server and website are protected against unauthorised access to your personal information. Our website servers are provided by a leading UK supplier with high security standards who have their own data centres in the UK.

## 6.1 Consent

When we send you promotional messages via email, including newsletters or job alerts, we rely on your consent. You can unsubscribe from these emails at any time by clicking on the “unsubscribe” link at the bottom of the email.

When you apply for a job through our website job application form we rely on your consent to share your application and CV with the recruiter or recruitment agent involved. We do not share this application with other recruiters or organisations. To withdraw consent for a job application you need to contact the recruiter or recruitment agent directly.

When you register with our CV database we rely on your consent for your details and CV to be shared with recruiters and agents operating on behalf of recruiters including our operatives. You can update or remove all your details from our CV database as specified above in section 4.3.

## 6.2 Legitimate interests

We may process data when it is in our legitimate interests to do so in operating our business and when these interests are not overridden by your data protection rights. Our legitimate interests include:

  * Personalising website content and emails to improve your job search experience (such as showing Saved Jobs, Job Alert categories or jobs relevant to you);
  * Sharing your application or CV with the employer, recruiter or recruitment agent during your job application;
  * Retaining anonymised or aggregate data that does not identify a person for analysis so we can improve our business and services;
  * Ensuring our websites and applications operate effectively and securely;
  * Handling customer contacts, queries, complaints or disputes.

## 6.3 For the performance of a contract

If you submit a job, email or call us we may process your data to deal with your request.

If you have any queries, concerns or amendments please contact us at dataprotection@eurojobsites.com, or write to us at our registered office at EuroJobsites Ltd, Unit 8, Kingsmill Business Park, Kingston Upon Thames, London KT1 3GZ, United Kingdom.

Any changes we may make to this policy in the future will be posted on this website so please check this page occasionally to ensure that you’re happy with any changes. If we make any significant changes we’ll make this clear on this website.

This Privacy Policy Summary was updated on 6th February 2019.
